[MUSIC].
Welcome to the Mastering Python Video Course,
in this video course
we are going to start with the fundamentals and then work our way
up to talk about more powerful and advanced techniques of python
programming. I'm Daniel Arbuckle and I'll be your presenter for
this course, I began using python approximately 20 years ago and
I've used it ever since for both research and professional work,
this first video is a quick sneak peek of the course as a whole
but we'll discuss the topics that we'll be covering throughout
the course, in the first section we'll look at how to get started
with python, we'll first walk through downloading and installing
the python interpreter in standard library,
then we'll take a look
at the python interactive shell and running python programs from
the command line, next we'll take a look at pip,
python's tool
for installing third party libraries and see how to find those
third part libraries using the python package index,
in section
two we'll talk through creating an empty python code package
and then extend that by adding code modules to the package,
will
then take a short detour to talk about how to import package modules
into each other and see how to add data files to the package,
in
section three we'll talk about best practices for python programmers,
these are the things that you don't have to do but the way they've
experienced it is a good idea,
here we'll talk about python's widely
accepted code formatting standard.
We'll see about using version control,
virtual environments for
developing code and how to format inland documentation,
and integrate
that documentation with testing.
In section four we'll put the theory on the back runner and cover
the practicalities of creating a command line program.
Here we'll talk about turning a package into a program,
handling
command line arguments and interacting with the programs user,
how
to start other programs from within our python codes and finally
how to start our program from a graphical user interface.
In
section five we move on to more advanced topics,
we're going to
take a look at how to run our code across multiple CPU's in CPU
course, we'll examine the concurrent.futures package in the python's
sender library,
which provides a simplified,
high level interface for launching
and working with background worker processes.
And then we'll look at the multiprocessing package which provides
a lower level interface to multiprocess programming.
In section 6, we're talking about asynchronous I/O and cooperative
threading with core routines.
We'll explain the difference between cooperative multithreading
and multiprocess programming.
And look at Python's built in asyncio package,
asyncio features
class specifically how the first synchronization back into existence
and those places where it's really needed and finally we will look
at using the tools we've covered in the prior videos to communicate
across the network.
In section 7 we will look at several ways in which Python code can
rewrite or change the meaning of other Python Code we will look
at function decorators,
function annotations, class decorators,
middle classes,
context managers and the descriptors.
We will wrap up with section 8 in which we'll be looking at how to
construct a slated view and test for a software.
We'll talk about the principles of unit testing,
using Python's built in unit
test package and using it
to smoke module to help control our test environment. Then we'll talk
about Unit test's discovery tool and wrap up with a discussion
of nodes a third party tool that has a range of useful testing
utilities.
The videos in this course are organized more or less in order from
fundamental to complex,
you are not tightly bound to that order
though so fell free to skip around if you wish.
This course is divided into two major parts,
for the first several
sections there's nothing you need except an interest for the topic,
we'll cover basics that will help you get started.
The later sections are more advanced at the minimum you should be
comfortable with the content of the basic sections before tackling
the advanced ones and even so practice and experience with Python
will be helpful.
Join me in the next video where we will be downloading and installing
Python.